# Joe Lee

# Experienced in IT Management, Graphics, Social Media, SEO, Sales and Marketing

Las Vegas, NV 89129 joeonlineusa@gmail.com (702) 203-2054

Seeking a challenging position where my 15+ years of experience in information technology, web development, SEO, graphic design, sales, marketing and business development skills will be utilized to improve computer efficiency, streamline operations, increase sales and improve profitability.

# Work Experience

### **Owner/Operator**

Superfast Computer Networks and Marketing - Anaheim, CA July 2007 to April 2021

Managed operations and business development for a computer consulting and marketing services company. Managed and serviced all company and customer equipment, including servers, WiFi access points, routers, firewalls, workstations, laptops, mobile and VoIP phone systems. Presented proposals and sales presentations to potential clients and sold service contracts. Managed all marketing activities and functions. Created, managed and updated all graphics and content for website design and online development. Designed, produced and provided print/digital marketing collateral, ads, brochures, flyers and postcards. Optimized websites to maximize SEO, search engine ranking, managed PPC and created promotions. Created and managed social media and customer engagement campaigns. Provided in-store and onsite services for PC, MAC, network administration, technical support, hardware upgrades, software troubleshooting, routine maintenance/updates and quick repairs/resolution.

#### IT Manager

Institute for Multicultural Counseling & Education Services (IMCES) - Los Angeles, CA September 2017 to December 2019

Managed all aspects of IT and support for a staff of 90+ employees and 150+ devices: servers, desktops, laptops, Macbooks, tablets and smartphones (Android and iPhones). Implemented migration to cloud based solutions: G Suite for Google Cloud. Monitored and managed network security. Created, managed and updated all graphics and content for website design, SEO, social media, and online development. Converted documents to browser fillable PDFs and deployed shared drives; greatly improving business efficiency. Trained staff on new technology. Improved internet throughput and WiFi access points. Managed administrative and operational tasks and projects. Created and managed various print/digital marketing collateral, photography, events, manuals, proposals, flyers and brochures.

#### Senior Network Engineer

TeamLogic IT - Torrance, CA November 2016 to May 2017

Provided technical expertise for a startup IT managed service provider. Serviced all company and customer equipment, including servers, workstations, laptops, mobile and VoIP phone systems. Assisted the owner during the sales process and presented proposals to potential clients and sold service

contracts. Provided in-store and onsite PC, MAC, network administration, technical support, hardware upgrades, software troubleshooting, routine equipment maintenance, updates and repairs.

# IT and Marketing Manager

Progressive Realty Partners - Irvine, CA May 2013 to October 2015

Managed all IT and marketing activities for a property management company specializing in the development/management of self-storage facilities and multi-family residential properties. Managed and serviced all company equipment, including servers, workstations, laptops, mobile and VOIP phone systems. Provided technical support for the entire enterprise which included: Trico Capital Investments, Hard Hat Builders, Storage Outlet and Lighthouse Storage. Managed all aspects of marketing: designed, produced and provided marketing collateral, brochures, postcards and print/online ads. Developed and managed several websites. Optimized websites to maximize search engine ranking, managed PPC campaigns and created promotions. Created and directed social media promotions and engagement campaigns which resulted in 500+ positive online reviews. Achieved record-breaking sales and exceeded goals.

### IT and Marketing Director

Hospitality Dental Associates and Glen Helen Raceway - San Bernardino, CA July 2002 to July 2007

Managed all IT functions and marketing activities for 8 dental offices, 6 orthodontic practices and a 256 acre motocross raceway facility. Managed technical operations, support and maintenance of network servers, end-user computers, Microsoft Exchange enterprise email and peripheral equipment. Maintained, modified and supported telephone data communications equipment. Provided technical support and training to onsite staff and 14 satellite offices. Developed, implemented and measured strategic marketing and communication programs. Designed, produced and provided all online and printed marketing collateral: direct mail promotions, brochures, postcards, newsletters, photography, videos, image manipulation, color correction, market research, creation of press releases and all other sales/marketing materials. Managed cable TV and radio media advertisements. Created, managed, maintained, updated and promoted multiple company websites. Configured websites to maximize search engine ranking and managed search engine marketing PPC campaigns. Produced and presented marketing for Preferred Employer Program to targeted prospects and at health fair trade shows. Organized and maintained marketing and IT budgets reports.

#### **Marketing Manager**

Pyro Spectaculars by Souza and Astro Pyrotechnics - Rialto, CA January 2001 to July 2002

Managed marketing and supported IT functions. Created, designed and produced proposals to meet specific RFP guidelines. Instrumental in establishing countless top-level clients including the Salt Lake City Olympics 2002 account. Sales Director quoted: "Couldn't have done it without you." Designed and created brochures, press kits, presentations, ads, generated leads, database management, direct-mail promotions, photography and video, image manipulation, color correction, research, creation of press releases and other sales and marketing collateral. Managed, upgraded and repaired all IT and provided technical support and training to staff on location as well as satellite offices. Purchased computers and equipment. Provided updates and promotions for multiple company websites.

#### **Network Engineer**

Computer Systems Design - Rancho Cucamonga, CA

November 2000 to January 2001

Provided onsite computer and network repair services. Resolved IT problems and issues. Troubleshooted, upgraded and repaired NT and Novell networks, PC, Mac, notebooks and all IT equipment. Consulted clients and increased sales. Provided customer service, telemarketing and sales support. Resolved all issues that senior technicians could not. Increased sales by creating and designing marketing promotions and collateral.

### **Information Systems Manager**

Palm Springs Life Magazine and Desert Publications - Palm Springs, CA October 1999 to November 2000

Managed, troubleshooted, upgraded and repaired computers, peripherals and digital equipment. Provided technical support and software training to over 60+ Mac and PC users on Microsoft NT and AppleTalk servers. Resolved over 1000+ hardware and software issues. Developed and implemented staff training. Assisted in web design, research, marketing and development. Consulted innovative ideas and ways to streamline operations.

### Marketing Manager/Webmaster/MIS

Character Collectibles and Vanmark - Fontana, CA December 1998 to October 1999

Created and maintained several company websites. Managed, upgraded and repaired company computers, laptops, servers, phone systems and equipment/peripherals. Provided technical support and computer training to over 45+ Mac and PC users networked to Microsoft NT and Novell servers. Launched new products to both wholesale and retail buyers. Published press releases into all trade magazines. Designed and created magazine ads and developed direct-mail promotions. Managed nationwide trade shows, designed, photographed and produced product catalogs. Created, organized, promoted and maintained collectors' clubs and new product launches. Provided vendors and clients with all digital graphic needs and various Internet requests. Developed digital photography studio and all marketing collateral to support sales and product development.

#### Marketing Manager/Webmaster/MIS

Jazz Speakers and Mpact Direct - Industry, CA April 1997 to December 1998

Created and maintained company websites and sold products to retailers and end-users. Researched and established major national accounts. Assisted in developing new USB products with industry leaders. Designed and produced direct-mail promotions and created print advertisements. Launched new products, established media relationships, distributed press releases and handled PR. Coordinated trade shows, designed catalogs, provided digital photography and other marketing collateral. Supported staff and clients with graphics and digital files. Managed, upgraded and repaired all company computers, servers, phone systems and peripherals. Provided technical support and training to staff, vendors and end-users.

#### Education

### **Management Information Systems and Mass Communications**

Cal State University - San Bernardino, CA

# Associate Degree: MIS, Marketing and Photography

Chaffey College - Rancho Cucamonga, CA

### Vocational Certificate: Multimedia Production and Graphic Design

Summit Career College - Colton, CA

### Skills

- Self-motivated professional with experience in IT, sales & marketing, website development, graphic design, B2C & B2B sales, account management, customer service, social media, technical support and server/network administration.
- Administration and maintenance of computer networks and related computing environments, including hardware, information systems, applications software, and all related equipment.
- Website design, development and maintenance. Write/edit edit content and design graphics. Create/launch social media programs and develop/administer marketing activities.
- Solid communicator with exceptional ability to create persuasive and effective sales documents, proposals and presentations. Results-driven achiever with strong organizational and time management skills with initiative to increase sales and profits.
- Advanced technical aptitude to quickly learn emerging technologies and effectively and efficiently train staff and clients on operating procedures, software applications and efficient solutions.
- Successfully resolved over 10k+ desktop support and server/network issues. Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve hardware, software, and other network and system problems. Identify IT problems, perform diagnostic testing and remediate issues. Install, configure, manage network and hardware/software, implement updates, upgrades, and patches. Implement/configure security measures, such as firewalls, routers and encryption.
- Expertise in Photoshop, graphic design, desktop publishing, product illustrations, company logos, interactive media, hi-res scanning, research, computer training, image-manipulation, digital photography and creation of sales/marketing collateral.
- Create/develop effective social media campaigns/programs maximizing exposure, brand positioning and increasing engagements. Optimize website, analyze search engine patterns and update content to improve organic SEO and ranking. Creation and management of PPC campaigns and promotions.
- Plan and implement network security measures to protect data. Monitor network and analyze server performance for load-balancing and optimize efficiency. Configure and maintain all software applications and administer security settings and modify Microsoft Server Active Directory security access and permissions. Process all hardware firmware updates and software upgrades.
- Identify/develop marketing strategies based on established objectives and market characteristics.
  Formulate, direct and execute marketing activities/strategies across multiple channels to increase sales of products and services. Coordinate and participate in promotional activities and trade shows.
- Conduct online marketing initiatives, paid ad placements, affiliate programs, sponsorship programs, email promotions and viral marketing campaigns. Collect and analyze data using web traffic metrics, grow link popularity and improve cost-per-clicks & click-through-rates.
- Determine specifications and define parameters for implementation of networks, routers, firewalls, access points, switches, controllers, security appliances and all other networking equipment. Monitor for intrusions or denial of service attacks and perform data backups and disaster recovery operations.

### Assessments

# Management & Leadership Skills: Planning & Execution — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Planning and managing resources to accomplish organizational goals

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Basic Maintenance and Repair — Expert**

June 2020

Performing basic repairs and maintenance for apartment complexes, office buildings, and other

facilities

Full results: Expert

### Office Manager — Expert

June 2020

Scheduling and budgeting

Full results: Expert

# **Business Analyst — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Analyzing information to solve business problems

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Basic Computer Skills: PC — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Mechanical Knowledge — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Understanding and applying mechanical concepts and processes.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Customer Focus & Orientation — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Attention to Detail — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### Workplace English — Expert

June 2020

Understanding spoken and written English in work situations.

Full results: Expert

### Following Directions — Expert

June 2020

Following multi-step instructions.

Full results: Expert

# **Business Math — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Using basic math to solve problems in a business context.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Working with MS Word Documents — Expert

June 2020

Knowledge of various Microsoft Word features, functions, and techniques.

Full results: Expert

# Composing & Sorting Email with Microsoft Outlook (PC) — Expert

June 2020

Effectively composing and organizing email messages in Microsoft Outlook.

Full results: Expert

# **General Manager (Hospitality) — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Solving group scheduling problems and reading and interpreting P&L statements

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Composing & Sorting Email with Gmail — Expert

June 2020

Effectively composing and organizing Gmail messages.

Full results: Expert

### Project Management Skills: Budgeting — Expert

June 2020

Managing project budgets by appropriately allocating and monitoring financial resources.

Full results: Expert

### Management & Leadership Skills: Impact & Influence — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Choosing the most effective strategy to inspire and influence others to meet business objectives.

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### **Project Timeline Management — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Prioritizing and allocating time to effectively achieve project deliverables

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Visual Merchandising — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Planning and maintaining commercial displays, interpreting planograms, and building relationships with store personnel.

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### Administrative Support — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Using basic scheduling and organizational skills in an office setting.

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Case Management & Social Work — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Prioritizing case tasks, gathering information, and providing services without judgment.

Full results: Highly Proficient

# **Construction Safety — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Using safe practices while on a construction site

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Electronic Medical Records: Best Practices — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Knowledge of EHR data, associated privacy regulations, and best practices for EHR use

Full results: Highly Proficient

# **Search Engine Optimization — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Interpreting online website performance metrics and understanding search engine optimization tactics

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Mechanical Skills: Monitoring — Expert

June 2020

Understanding of machine dials, gauges, displays, and data charts.

Full results: Expert

### Manufacturing: Quality Inspection — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Making precise measurements, reading prints, and making pass/fail decisions.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Outside Sales — Expert**

June 2020

Actively listening and responding appropriately; performing common sales calculations.

Full results: Expert

### **Inside Sales — Expert**

June 2020

Actively listening and responding appropriately; performing common sales calculations.

Full results: Expert

### **Delivery Driver — Expert**

June 2020

Interpreting instructions, reading maps, and solving problems.

Full results: Expert

### Filing & Organization — Expert

June 2020

Arranging and managing information or materials using a set of rules.

Full results: Expert

# Scheduling — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Cross-referencing agendas and itineraries to avoid scheduling conflicts.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Active Listening — Expert**

June 2020

Actively listening and appropriately responding in conversations

Full results: Expert

### Social Media — Highly Proficient

June 2020

Creating content, communicating online, and building a brand's reputation.

Full results: Highly Proficient

# **Technical Support — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Verbal Communication — Expert**

June 2020

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely

Full results: Expert

# **Automotive Maintenance — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Knowledge of vehicles, vehicle maintenance, and repairs.

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### Real Estate — Expert

June 2020

Matching listings with specifications

Full results: Expert

#### **Data Entry: Attention to Detail — Expert**

June 2020

Maintaining data integrity by detecting errors

Full results: Expert

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.